<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-24T23:43:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">anonDissent’s Investigations</title><subtitle>Investigation Repo</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Who does JD Vance Follow on Twitter? Part One</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/24/JD-Vance-follows-part-one/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who does JD Vance Follow on Twitter? Part One" /><published>2025-02-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/24/JD-Vance-follows-part-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/24/JD-Vance-follows-part-one/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="why-do-twitter-x-follows-matter">Why do Twitter (X) follows matter?</h2>

<p>Before launching into a series on who JD Vance follows, I’d like to outline why I think this is even a useful exercise.</p>

<p>Engagement is at the core of social media algorithms. This is an oversimplification, but generally speaking the more
that users engage with a profile (via clicks, likes, retweets, follows, etc.) the more that profile is shown to
other users</p>

<p>When large public figures on Twitter engages with other social media accounts, they expose those accounts to their follows
either directly via retweets or comments, or indirectly via <strong>For You</strong> or <strong>Who to follow</strong> sections of the Twitter
UI.</p>

<p>A large public figure’s engagement has even greater network effects, beyond their own following. The networks of public
figures amplify the engagement to even wider nets of followers.</p>

<p>For example, JD Vance has a respectable <strong>3.7M followers</strong>, Trump has <strong>101.6M followers</strong> , and Elon has
<strong>218.8M followers</strong>. While JD Vance directly only has the <strong>3.7M followers</strong> his proximity to Trump and Elon
gives the information and accounts he engages with a much wider audience.</p>

<p>Does this mean if JD Vance retweets an account it will reach all of Elon and Trump’s followers? No
However, things he tweets are more likely to get retweeted by Trump and Elon, and sources JD uses are
more likely to be trusted by Trump, Elon, and other right-wing figures as well. Due to his proximity to Trump,
Elon, and other right-wing figures JD Vance’s influence extends greatly beyond his <strong>3.7M followers</strong>.</p>

<p>To what extent does it extend? That is unclear and would require some sophisticated data analytics that I’m not
equipped to carry out</p>

<p>Some things I would be interested in knowing to test some of the claims above are as follows:</p>

<ul>
  <li>How much does a Trump, Elon, or Vance retweet “boost” an account?</li>
  <li>How often do Trump or Elon retweet Vance?</li>
  <li>Can we identify a Vance influence on Trump, Elon, or other large right-wing figures? (For example, Vance introducing
some anon account to the other major figures)</li>
  <li>Can we identify Vance’s major influences?</li>
</ul>

<p>Let me also be clear, JD Vance does not need a large following for us to be concerned about who he follows and
what he reposts. He is the Vice President of the United States, a heartbeat away from being the most powerful man
on Earth, we should be concerned about who he follows <strong>no matter</strong> how many followers he has.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why do Twitter (X) follows matter?]]></summary></entry></feed>